<modDesc descVersion="104">
    <author>Arrow_Kb, ConGan98</author>
	<source>Github</source>
    <version>1.1.0.1</version>
    <title>
        <en>Animal Herding - Lite</en>
        <de>Tierhaltung – Lite</de>
        <fr>Élevage D'Animaux - Lite</fr>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en>
        <![CDATA[ This mod allows all animals to be dynamically herded at will. When they are being herded, animals will walk away from the player, allowing them to be interactively moved between pastures. The Lite version of this mod only handles herding between husbandries, whereas the full version contains more dynamic custom features such as path finding, husbandry navigation, possibility of custom animations, individual behaviours and more, moving the entirety of the visual animal system from the engine to LUA scripts, allowing for much more mod control over animals.

Animals will stop for structures, objects, vehicles and other animals, allowing you to create routes for them to follow, such as in the screenshots provided.

Animals respond to players in vehicles as well as players on foot, allowing the use of vehicles such as quad bikes to herd them. Animals can be moved in the following ways:
- Walking towards them: animals will try to move away from the player
- While holding a feed bucket: animals will try to follow the player
- By being picked up: small/young (or light animals with RealisticLivestock enabled) can be picked up and moved around manually

To start herding, you must be inside a husbandry and then press the "Start Herding" button (default left shift + n). All visual animals in that husbandry will then become herdable and will respond to the player

Herded animals will automatically be moved into a husbandry when they walk inside it, with the exception of the original husbandry where they came from which will only become available for them after leaving the husbandry for a certain amount of time. Alternatively, you can press the "Stop Herding" button, and all herded animals will be moved into the closest husbandry to their current position, if there is one available.

It is not recommended to herd animals in sheds with very high flooring, as the animals may get stuck.

This mod is fully compatible with multiplayer, with the exception of being able to pickup animals.

Compatible with RealisticLivestock, EnhancedAnimalSystem and Animal Package Vanilla Edition

HandTools:
- Feed Bucket: can be purchased in the Animal Tools section of the store
- Animal: approach an animal (herded or not) and press the relevant button in the context menu to pickup a valid animal. Holding an animal prevents the player from switching or toggling handTools until moved into a valid husbandry. Chickens may only be picked up when they are being herded.

Changelog:

1.1.0.1
- Fixed some mod incompatibilities

1.1.0.0
- Added multiplayer support
- Added ability to pickup young/small animals (RealisticLivestock has an additional weight check)
- Added ability to herd animals towards the player while using a feed bucket (purchasable in the store)
- Added rear player detection; animals will no longer turn when a player is directly behind them
- Added map hotspots for herded animals
- Added compatibility with Animal Package Vanilla Edition
- Improved obstacle avoidance
- Improved side collision detection when next to a fence/wall
- Improved husbandry detection when stopping herding
- Fixed incorrectly calculated movement speed
- Fixed idle -> walk animation transition
- Fixed animal collision proxies banging into nearby vehicles ]]>
        </en>
        <de>
        <![CDATA[ Mit diesem Mod können alle Tiere nach Belieben dynamisch zusammengetrieben werden. Wenn sie zusammengetrieben werden, entfernen sich die Tiere vom Spieler, sodass sie interaktiv zwischen Weiden hin- und herbewegt werden können. Die Lite-Version dieses Mods unterstützt nur das Hüten zwischen Viehzuchtbetrieben, während die Vollversion dynamischere benutzerdefinierte Funktionen wie Wegfindung, Navigation in der Viehzucht, die Möglichkeit benutzerdefinierter Animationen, individuelle Verhaltensweisen und mehr enthält, wodurch das gesamte visuelle Tiersystem von der Engine auf LUA-Skripte verlagert wird, was eine viel bessere Mod-Kontrolle über die Tiere ermöglicht.

Die Tiere halten vor Gebäuden, Objekten, Fahrzeugen und anderen Tieren an, sodass Sie Routen für sie erstellen können, wie in den bereitgestellten Screenshots zu sehen ist.

Die Tiere reagieren sowohl auf Spieler in Fahrzeugen als auch auf Spieler zu Fuß, sodass Sie Fahrzeuge wie Quads zum Hüten verwenden können. Tiere können auf folgende Weise bewegt werden:
- Auf sie zugehen: Die Tiere versuchen, sich vom Spieler zu entfernen.
- Mit einem Futterkübel in der Hand: Die Tiere versuchen, dem Spieler zu folgen.
- Durch Aufheben: Kleine/junge (oder leichte Tiere, bei denen „RealisticLivestock” aktiviert ist) können aufgehoben und manuell bewegt werden.

Um mit dem Hüten zu beginnen, müssen Sie sich in einem Stall befinden und dann die Taste „Hüten starten” drücken (standardmäßig linke Umschalttaste + n). Alle sichtbaren Tiere in diesem Stall können dann gehütet werden und reagieren auf den Spieler.

Gehütete Tiere werden automatisch in einen Stall gebracht, wenn sie ihn betreten, mit Ausnahme des ursprünglichen Stalls, aus dem sie gekommen sind, der ihnen erst wieder zur Verfügung steht, wenn sie den Stall für eine bestimmte Zeit verlassen haben. Alternativ können Sie die Taste „Hüten beenden“ drücken, woraufhin alle gehüteten Tiere in den nächstgelegenen Stall gebracht werden, sofern einer verfügbar ist.

Es wird nicht empfohlen, Tiere in Ställen mit sehr hohem Boden zu hüten, da die Tiere dort stecken bleiben können.

Dieser Mod ist vollständig mit dem Mehrspielermodus kompatibel, mit Ausnahme der Möglichkeit, Tiere aufzunehmen.

Kompatibel mit RealisticLivestock, EnhancedAnimalSystem und Animal Package Vanilla Edition

Handwerkzeuge:
- Futterkübel: kann im Bereich „Tierwerkzeuge” des Shops gekauft werden
- Tier: Nähern Sie sich einem Tier (ob in der Herde oder nicht) und drücken Sie die entsprechende Taste im Kontextmenü, um ein gültiges Tier aufzunehmen. Das Halten eines Tieres verhindert, dass der Spieler die Handwerkzeuge wechseln oder umschalten kann, bis es in einen gültigen Stall gebracht wurde. Hühner können nur aufgenommen werden, wenn sie in der Herde sind. ]]>
        </de>
        <fr>
        <![CDATA[ Ce mod permet de rassembler tous les animaux de manière dynamique à volonté. Lorsqu'ils sont rassemblés, les animaux s'éloignent du joueur, ce qui permet de les déplacer de manière interactive entre les pâturages. La version Lite de ce mod ne gère que le rassemblement entre les élevages, tandis que la version complète contient des fonctionnalités personnalisées plus dynamiques telles que la recherche de chemin, la navigation entre les élevages, la possibilité d'animations personnalisées, des comportements individuels et plus encore, déplaçant l'intégralité du système visuel des animaux du moteur vers des scripts LUA, ce qui permet un contrôle beaucoup plus important des animaux par le mod.

Les animaux s'arrêteront devant les structures, les objets, les véhicules et les autres animaux, ce qui vous permettra de créer des itinéraires à suivre, comme dans les captures d'écran fournies.

Les animaux réagissent aux joueurs dans les véhicules ainsi qu'aux joueurs à pied, ce qui permet d'utiliser des véhicules tels que des quads pour les rassembler. Les animaux peuvent être déplacés de la manière suivante :
- En marchant vers eux : les animaux essaieront de s'éloigner du joueur
- En tenant un seau de nourriture : les animaux essaieront de suivre le joueur
- En les soulevant : les petits/jeunes animaux (ou les animaux légers avec RealisticLivestock activé) peuvent être soulevés et déplacés manuellement

Pour commencer à rassembler les animaux, vous devez vous trouver à l'intérieur d'une exploitation agricole, puis appuyer sur le bouton « Start Herding » (par défaut, shift gauche + n). Tous les animaux visibles dans cette exploitation agricole pourront alors être rassemblés et réagiront au joueur

Les animaux rassemblés seront automatiquement déplacés vers une exploitation agricole lorsqu'ils y entreront, à l'exception de l'exploitation d'origine d'où ils proviennent, qui ne leur sera accessible qu'après avoir quitté l'exploitation pendant un certain temps. Vous pouvez également appuyer sur le bouton « Arrêter le rassemblement » et tous les animaux rassemblés seront déplacés vers l'exploitation agricole la plus proche de leur position actuelle, s'il y en a une de disponible.

Il n'est pas recommandé de regrouper les animaux dans des étables dont le sol est très haut, car ils risquent de rester coincés.

Ce mod est entièrement compatible avec le mode multijoueur, à l'exception de la possibilité de ramasser des animaux.

Compatible avec RealisticLivestock, EnhancedAnimalSystem et Animal Package Vanilla Edition

Outils manuels :
- Seau d'alimentation : peut être acheté dans la section « Outils pour animaux » de la boutique
- Animal : approchez-vous d'un animal (en troupeau ou non) et appuyez sur le bouton correspondant dans le menu contextuel pour ramasser un animal valide. Le fait de tenir un animal empêche le joueur de changer ou d'activer les outils manuels tant qu'il n'a pas été déplacé vers une exploitation agricole valide. Les poulets ne peuvent être ramassés que lorsqu'ils sont en troupeau. ]]>
        </fr>
    </description>
    <iconFilename>icon_AnimalHerdingLite.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
	<l10n filenamePrefix="translations/translation"/>
    <extraSourceFiles>
		<sourceFile filename="src/handTools/HandTool.lua"/>
		<sourceFile filename="src/handTools/HandTools.lua"/>
		<sourceFile filename="src/handTools/HandToolSystem.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/player/PlayerInputComponent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/Medium.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
    <dependencies>
        <dependency>FS25_RealisticLivestockRM</dependency>
    </dependencies>
	<inputBinding>
		<actionBinding action="HerdingLite">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_n"/>
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="HerdingLiteUnload">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_u"/>
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="HerdingLiteDog">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_b"/>
		</actionBinding>
	</inputBinding>
	<actions>
		<action name="HerdingLite"/>
		<action name="HerdingLiteUnload"/>
		<action name="HerdingLiteDog"/>
	</actions>
</modDesc>